detail-online.com 2019-03-22

# Privacy Statement- DETAIL - Magazine of Architecture + Construction Details

### Data Protection DSGVO 2018

Your data is in safe hands with us. The processing of your personal data at www.detail-online.com, www.detail-business-information.com (homepage) and shop.detail.de (webshop) and when you use our app is done in line with the applicable data protection legislation. With this Privacy Statement we wish to inform you of how your personal data is actually processed when you visit our websites and use our app.

Privacy Statement from: March 2018

 **2\. Data collected and the purpose of data processing**  
We collect personal data on the basis of your consent to fulfil a contract with you and/or to fulfil a statutory obligation. Personal data is all information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

 **2.1 Usage data**  
Whenever you visit our homepage, the webshop or use our app we collect usage data: 

  * Time and date of your access
  * Browser type and version
  * Operating system
  * Computer data
  * IP address (anonymised).

We store this usage data separately from other information. We process the usage data only for statistical purposes, to ensure system security, for technical improvement and to optimise the service offered.

 **2.2 Data when ordering from the webshop**  
When you place an order in our webshop we collect the following data:

  * Name 
  * Address
  * Telephone no.
  * E-mail address 
  * Payment data
  * VAT no. (optional)
  * Fax (optional)

We process the personal data collected from you because it is needed to complete the transaction.   
In addition you have the option of registering in our webshop using the data stated above. In this case we store the stated data and your order history in your profile.

 **2.3 Data when using DETAIL Inspiration**  
If you want to use our DETAIL project portfolio with the service DETAIL inspiration you must register for this. For this we collect the following information: 

  * User name
  * Password 
  * Name
  * Usage data (log files, access data, downloads)

We process the personal data collected from you in order to provide the service DETAIL inspiration. 

 **3\. Data disclosure**  
Personal data will only be disclosed to third parties or contractors of order processors if this is necessary for the relevant purposes. We pass on personal data to specialised service providers, for instance dispatch and payment service providers. Disclosure to foreign states occurs only where this is expressly stated in this Privacy Statement.   
In so doing, we ensure through appropriate measures that the third parties provide an appropriate level of protection for the personal data.

 **4\. Deletion of the data**  
The stored personal data is deleted when you rescind your consent to its processing, when the data is no longer needed to fulfil the purpose pursued by its storage or when storage of the data is or becomes inadmissible for other legal reasons. Upon deletion or freezing of the data the corresponding services can no longer be used.

 **5\. Newsletter and e-mail advertising  
5.1 Newsletter**  
We are happy to keep you informed about exciting projects, news from our blog on architectural and design topics, worthwhile information on research and current events in our newsletter, if you have given your consent to this or if this is in line with statutory regulations.  
With your registration (double opt-in procedure) for the newsletter you declare your consent to receive the newsletter. The data collected (title, name, e-mail address) is used only to send the newsletter.   
Our newsletter is sent by Agnitas, a service provided by AGNITAS AG. The data protection regulations of Agnitas can be found here: [www.agnitas.de/datensicherheit/](https://www.agnitas.de/datensicherheit/). Agnitas collects and processes usage data of the newsletter. The data collected is used for technical improvement and optimisation of newsletter service.  
You can rescind your consent to receive the newsletter and the associated processing of data at any time. Rescission is effected via a link in the newsletter or by informal notification to DETAIL Business Information GmbH, Messerschmittstraße 4, 80992 Munich or an e-mail to maildo not copy and be happy@detaildot or no dot.de.

 **5.2 E-mail advertising in accordance with § 7 (3) UWG**  
We are entitled within the context of the statutory permission under § 7 (3) of the German Act Against Unfair Competition (UWG) to use the e-mail address given by you in your order for direct advertising for similar products or services of our own. If you no longer wish to receive advertising for similar products or services you can unsubscribe your e-mail address at any time without incurring any costs other than the costs of transmission in line with basic rates. The possibility to unsubscribe is contained in every advertising e-mail.

 **6\. Competitions**  
If you participate in a competition we collect the personal data you provide in order to run the competition and for statistical purposes.   
In order to inform you of the results of the competition we send an e-mail to the address you provide. Your personal data is passed on only to the competition partners for informing you of a win.  
The stored personal data is deleted when this is no longer needed for the competition or when its storage is or becomes inadmissible for other legal reasons. 

**7\. Surveys  
** For DETAIL online surveys we use TYPEFORM, a service by TYPEFORM S.L. (“TYPEFORM”), to improve and optimise our offer. If you take part in an online survey by DETAIL we collect the following data:

  * Survey usage and duration 
  * Browser type and version
  * Operating system
  * IP address (anonymised)
  * Location
  * Sociodemographic details (voluntary)
  * Position (voluntary)
  * Employment field (voluntary)
  * Size of enterprise (voluntary)
  * Title, first name, surname (voluntary, for participation in prize draw)
  * E-mail address (voluntary, for participation in prize draw)

The data collected about you is processed by us for evaluation of the online survey. All details given by you are evaluated in anonymised form. You are not obliged to give personal data to participate in the survey. Further information on conditions of use and data protection can be found under [admin.typeform.com/to/dwk6gt](https://admin.typeform.com/to/dwk6gt). We process your voluntary details if you participate in our prize draw exclusively to carry out the prize draw and not for evaluation of the survey.

 **8\. Events  
8.1 P** **articipation in an DETAIL event:  
** When you register for an event by DETAIL we collect the following data:

  * Firm
  * Name 
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * E-mail address 
  * Payment details may be necessary in the case of events requiring payment.

The personal data collected about you is processed by us because we need it to complete the transaction.  If we are organising the event together with a named partner your data will also be passed on to the partner for order settlement. 

**8.2 Events** **  via Xing Events**  
For event registrations we use Xing-Events, a service provided by Xing SE ("Xing"). If you wish to register for an event organised by Xing-Events you will be transferred to the event site of Xing-Events. There you have the option of registering for the event or buying a ticket.   
When buying tickets or registering, Xing collects the data provided by participants and then passes this on to the organiser of the event. Collection and transmission of the data is necessary to fulfil the contract (e.g. to check admissions at the event).  
When using this service the data protection regulations of [Xing](https://www.xing.com/privacy "Opens internal link in current window") and [Xing-Events ](https://www.xing-events.com/sub-footer/datenschutz/ "Opens internal link in current window")apply. 

 **9\. Your rights  
9.1 Right of rescission**  
You have the right to rescind the consents you have given to the processing of your personal data at any time with effect for the future.   
Such rescission does not affect the legality of processing done on the basis of your consent up to the date of rescission.

 **9.2 Right to information**  
You have the right to demand to be informed free of charge of the personal data stored. If you so request, the information can also be sent electronically. 

 **9.3 Correction, deletion and restriction of data**  
You have the right to demand the correction, deletion or restriction of the personal data relating to you. Upon deletion or blocking of your data, you will however no longer be able to use the associated services.  
Your right to deletion can be excluded by statutory retention duties.

 **9.4 Data export**  
You have the right to receive from us in machine-readable form the data which we process through automatic procedures and to whose usage you have given your consent, or to have this data transmitted to other responsible persons.

 **9.5 Enforcement of your rights**  
You can enforce your rights by sending an informal notification to DETAIL Business Information GmbH, Messerschmittstraße 4, 80992 Munich or an e-mail to datenschutzdo not copy and be happy@detaildot or no dot.de.  
In case of complaints you can also contact the responsible supervisory authority for data protection in Ansbach.

 **10\. Data security**  
We protect your personal data from risks associated with data processing, in particular unauthorised access, utilisation or publication. For this purpose we have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place which are in line with the latest technological standards. 

 **11\. Cookies and tracking tools  
** We use temporary session cookies and permanent cookies. Cookies are text files which are stored on your terminal and which enable an analysis of how the homepage, webshop and app are used. We use cookies and other data collection tools to collect data which helps us to personalise the services we offer.

For this we use the following tools:

 **11.1 Google Analytics**  
The homepage and webshop use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics enables analysis of how users are utilising the site. The information collected includes, e.g. information on the operating system, screen, your IP address, website views called up, the date and time of your visit to our website. The information created on your use of the website is generally transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. We have activated IP anonymisation. This means that your IP address will be shortened by Google before transmission within the Member States of the European Union or in other states which are signatories to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address by transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google uses this information on behalf of the website operator to analyse your use of the website, compile reports on activities within the app and to provide other services associated with use of the website to the provider of the app. The IP address transmitted within the context of Google Analytics is not associated with other information by Google.  
You can prevent the transmission of data related to your use of the website (including your IP address) to Google and processing of this data by Google by [deactivating Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Opens internal link in current window") in your browser. 

Further information on conditions of use and data protection can be found at [www.google.com/analytics/terms/](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/) or [policies.google.com](https://policies.google.com/). We wish to inform you that the configuration of Google Analytics on this website ensures the anonymised collection of IP addresses (known as IP masking). 

**11.2 Google AdWords**  
Our online shop uses the online advertising program “Google AdWords,” the online marketing system of Google Inc. (“Google”) and in this context conversion tracking (evaluation of visit actions). For this, Google AdWords creates a cookie on your computer if you land on our website via a Google advert.  
These cookies lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. This means that there is no possibility that cookies can be traced via the websites of AdWords customers. The information collected using the conversion cookie serves the purpose of creating conversion statistics. We are informed of the anonymous overall number of users who have clicked on our advert and been directed to a site fitted with a conversion tracking tag, but we do not receive any information which would enable the personal identification of users.  
You can prevent collection of data on your use of adverts and the processing of this data through Google by deactivating Google Adwords in your browser. 

Further information on data usage by Google, possible settings and objections and the privacy policy of Google AdWords can be found under [policies.google.com/technologies/ads](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads). Settings for how adverts are displayed by Google can be changed under [adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). 

**10.3 SZMnG  
** Our website and webshop use the measuring procedure (“SZMnG”) of INFOnline GmbH to determine statistical characteristic values about use of the services we offer. The purpose of measuring the range is to determine statistically the intensity of use, the number of users of a website and the surfing behaviour – on the basis of a unified standard procedure – and thus to obtain comparable values across the market.For all digital providers who are members of IVW (Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e.V.  \- Information community to establish the scope of advertisers) or participate in studies by AGOF (Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V.  -Working Group for Online Research), the usage statistics are published regularly by AGOF, agma (Arbeitsgemeinschaft Media-Analyse e.V. - Working group for media analysis) and IVW and these can be viewed on the relevant websites. If you do not wish to participate in the measurements you can opt out using following the link: [optout.ioam.de.&nbsp](http://optout.ioam.de.%26nbsp/);

Further information on conditions of use and data protection can be found at [https://www.infonline.de/datenschutz/benutzer/.](https://www.infonline.de/datenschutz/benutzer/)

 **11.4 ADTECH**  
Our homepage and our online shop use advertising cookies of the provider ADTECH. For this the cookie under an anonymous user profile records the browser type, operating system and user behaviour (e.g. clicked advertising banners, subpages visited, anonymised surveys, etc.). This data is used for the purposes of showing you content and adverts in line with your interests and can be used for internal statistical analysis.  
If you no longer wish to receive usage-based advertising inserts you can object under the following links and deactivate the collection of data: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out-interface>  
Thereafter ADTECH will no longer create advertising cookies on your browser.

 **12\. Social Plugins**  
We use social plugins ("plugins") of social networks.  
In order to increase the protection of your data when using our website, these plugins are not unrestricted, but instead are only incorporated into the site using HTML links (known as the "Shariff solution"). This ensures that using the site does not enable the creation of any connection to the servers of the provider of the relevant social network. When you click on one of the social media buttons a new window is opened and the page of the relevant service provider is called up on which you (possibly after entering your login data) can, for instance, press the Like or Share button.  
Please see the data protection information of the providers for details as to the purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of the data by the providers on their sites, as well as your rights in this respect and configuration options for the protection of your privacy.
